Department of English fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Department of English fonds
1965 - 1997, predominant 1965 - 1980
F-25
2 m of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
DATES OF CREATION The predominant dates of the material are 1965-1980. Post-1980 records consist of publications and course offering booklets.
Department of English
The Department of English was established by the Board of Governors in April 1964, and began to offer courses within the Faculty of Arts at the Bachelor level when the University opened in 1965. The Department's offerings were expanded with the addition in 1966 of a Master's program and in 1974 with the approval of a Ph.D. program. The Department was responsible, through its Head, for the promotion of research and the development and delivery of programs in the field of composition and English-language literature. An adjunct to this function was its responsibility to help in the development and instruction in non-departmental programs such as Women's Studies, Fine and Performing Arts, Canadian Studies, and the Humanities minor program.
The Department's activities included participation in University and external associations and committees, and the organization of and participation in conferences. Several faculty members were involved in the publication of literary journals. These include West Coast Review, which began in 1965 and later became independent of the Department; Line, edited by Roy Miki and devoted to the University's Contemporary Literature Collection; and Tessera, a feminist journal edited by Kathy Mezei. In 1990, West Coast Review and Line were joined to form West Coast Line.
The Department was administered by a chair and a number of standing committees, as laid down in a Department constitution in 1968. In the formalized Department Constitution approved 1 August 1975, the Chair was responsible for the overall administration of the Department, which included "The devising and apportioning of the budget; The assignment of teaching duties, with the advice of the Graduate and Undergraduate Curriculum Committees; Calling and conducting Departmental meetings; Mediating all disputes within the Department; [and] Initiating course grade appeal procedures."
The number of Department committees changed greatly over time. In 1965 the Department consisted of five standing committees which had an advisory role: Curriculum (ad hoc), Appointments, Promotions and Salary Increases, Library, and Invited Speakers. There were also loosely organized committees of those teaching each first- and second-year course, usually chaired by the lecturer. By 1968 the number of committees had expanded to ten to include: the Policy Committee; Steering Committee, which was the chief advisory body to the Chair; Honours Committee; Teaching Evaluation Committee; Student Load Committee; Search and Selection Committee; Graduate Admissions Committee; Undergraduate Studies Committee; and West Coast Review, responsible for the publication of the journal.
In the Constitution of 1975, it stated that the Department would consist of four elected and two non-elected standing committees. Those elected committees included the Graduate Curriculum Committee, the Undergraduate Curriculum Committee, the Departmental Tenure Committee, and the Appointments Committee. Those appointed committees included the Library and Invited Speakers committees. After 1975, a Composition Committee was also struck.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the name of the body.
The fonds of the Department of English consists of records created and received in the course of the administration of the department and the carrying out of its functions of providing instruction and promoting research. The activities documented include policy and procedures development; the planning, initiation and administration of curriculum and programs; departmental and faculty meetings; faculty salary, appointment, promotion and tenure deliberations; departmental reviews; and the publication of journals and reports. The types of documents include meeting agenda, correspondence, course outlines and examinations, an external review, faculty files, memoranda, minutes of meetings, and reports.
The titles and arrangement of series were provided by the archivist.
Buitenhuis, Peter; Zaslove, Jerald; Alderson, Evan W.; Newman, Gerald M.; Harden, Edgar F.; Baker, Ron
The records were transferred in a number of accessions from the Department, beginning in the early 1980s.
Additional material has been accessioned but not yet processed as of September 2002 (2.33 m., 1968-1993). Please consult the archivist for information about using these materials; restrictions may apply. Further accruals are expected.
Consult the inventory of the Faculty of Arts fonds, F-2; as well as the inventory of the West Coast Review / Line fonds, F-81.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
File lists are available.
- Policies and procedures, 1975; F-25-1; 1 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of the Department Constitution.
  Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as required by law. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  - Constitution, 1975; F-25-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    Textual records
    Open
- Correspondence, 1965 - 1979; F-25-2; 1.35 m of textual records
  Series consists of correspondence received and sent by the Department Chair. It includes memoranda and reports.
  - Chronological correspondence, 1965 - 1979; F-25-2-1; 1.13 m of textual records
    - Chronological correspondence, 1965; F-25-2-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
      Restricted in whole
    - Chronological correspondence, 1965; F-25-2-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1965; F-25-2-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1965; F-25-2-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
      Pending review
    - Chronological correspondence, 1965; F-25-2-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1965; F-25-2-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1966; F-25-2-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1966; F-25-2-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1969; F-25-2-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1969; F-25-2-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1969; F-25-2-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 25-1)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1970; F-25-2-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1970; F-25-2-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1970; F-25-2-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1970; F-25-2-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1970; F-25-2-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1970; F-25-2-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1970; F-25-2-1-0-17.1 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1970; F-25-2-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1971; F-25-2-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1971; F-25-2-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1971; F-25-2-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 25-2)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1972; F-25-2-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 25-3)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1972; F-25-2-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 25-3)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1972; F-25-2-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 25-3)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1972; F-25-2-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 25-3)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1972; F-25-2-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 25-3)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1972; F-25-2-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 25-3)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1973; F-25-2-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 25-3)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1973; F-25-2-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 25-3)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1973; F-25-2-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 25-3)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1973; F-25-2-1-0-31 (Archival box - standard 25-4)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1973; F-25-2-1-0-32 (Archival box - standard 25-4)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1973; F-25-2-1-0-33 (Archival box - standard 25-4)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1973; F-25-2-1-0-34 (Archival box - standard 25-4)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1973; F-25-2-1-0-35 (Archival box - standard 25-4)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1973; F-25-2-1-0-36 (Archival box - standard 25-4)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-37 (Archival box - standard 25-4)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-38 (Archival box - standard 25-4)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-39 (Archival box - standard 25-4)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-40 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-41 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-42 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-43 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-44 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-45 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-46 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-47 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1974; F-25-2-1-0-48 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-49 (Archival box - standard 25-5)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-50 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-51 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-52 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-53 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-54 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-55 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-56 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-57 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-58 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-59 (Archival box - standard 25-6)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-60 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-61 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-62 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-63 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-64 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-65 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-66 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-67 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-68 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-69 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-70 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-71 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-72 (Archival box - standard 25-7)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-73 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-74 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-75 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-76 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-77 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-78 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-79 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-80 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-81 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-82 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-83 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1979; F-25-2-1-0-84 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1979; F-25-2-1-0-85 (Archival box - standard 25-8)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1979; F-25-2-1-0-86 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence, 1979; F-25-2-1-0-87 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-88 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-89 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1975; F-25-2-1-0-90 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-91 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-92 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1976; F-25-2-1-0-93 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-94 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-95 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1977; F-25-2-1-0-96 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-97 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
    - Chronological correspondence - Graduate Studies, 1978; F-25-2-1-0-98 (Archival box - standard 25-9)
  - Memoranda, 1965 - 1977; F-25-2-2; 7 cm of textual records
    - Office of the President, 1965 - 1968; F-25-2-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Vice-President, Academic, 1973; F-25-2-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Chair's Memoranda, 1977; F-25-2-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Memoranda to Faculty, 1965 - 1966; F-25-2-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
      Restricted in part
    - Memoranda to Faculty, 1967; F-25-2-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Memoranda to Faculty, 1968; F-25-2-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Memoranda to Faculty, 1969; F-25-2-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Memoranda to Faculty, 1970; F-25-2-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Memoranda to Faculty, 1976 - 1977; F-25-2-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Chair's Engagements, 1968 - 1970; F-25-2-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Chair's Engagements, 1965 - 1967; F-25-2-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Ethnomusicology, 1966; F-25-2-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Publications Management Committee - Three Universities Press, 1967 - 1968; F-25-2-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
  - Subject files, 1965 - 1979; F-25-2-3; 13 cm of textual records
    - A.E. Sawyer Memorial Prize, 1965 - 1967; F-25-2-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Academic Symposium, 1966; F-25-2-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Curriculum, 1966; F-25-2-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Danforth Foundation, 1966; F-25-2-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Interim Council, 1968; F-25-2-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Nepotism, 1965; F-25-2-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - New Building, 1966; F-25-2-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Noranda Lectures, 1966; F-25-2-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Recruiting, 1966 - 1967; F-25-2-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Reference Letters, 1966 - 1967; F-25-2-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Religious Studies, 1965 - 1966; F-25-2-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Student Society, 1966; F-25-2-3-0-12 (Archival box - standard 25-10)
    - Troika Evaluations, 1973; F-25-2-3-0-13 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - U.N.E.S.C.O., 1966; F-25-2-3-0-14 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - Visiting Speakers, 1972 - 1973; F-25-2-3-0-15 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - Visiting Speakers, 1974; F-25-2-3-0-16 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - Visiting Speakers, 1975; F-25-2-3-0-17 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - Visiting Speakers, 1976; F-25-2-3-0-18 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - Visiting Speakers, 1977; F-25-2-3-0-19 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - Visiting Speakers, 1978; F-25-2-3-0-20 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - Visiting Speakers, 1979; F-25-2-3-0-21 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
  - Printed materials and reports, 1965 - 1967; F-25-2-4; 2 cm of textual records
    - Faculty Handbook, 1967; F-25-2-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - Reports, 1966; F-25-2-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
    - Releases, 1965; F-25-2-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
- Faculty members, 1965 - 1978; F-25-3; 2 cm of textual records
  Series consists of files related to the appointment, salary, and tenure of faculty members, as well as research grants. It includes correspondence, curricula vitae, memoranda and reports.
  - Faculty Lists, 1977 - 1978; F-25-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
  - Appointments, 1972 - 1973; F-25-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
  - Research Grants, 1965 - 1970; F-25-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 25-11)
- Departmental committees, 1966 - 1977; F-25-4; 12 cm of textual records
  Series consists of the records of various departmental committees. It includes circulars, correspondence, minutes of meetings, and memoranda.
  - Composition committee, 1977; F-25-4-1; 1 cm of textual records
    - Composition Committee, 1977; F-25-4-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Honours committee, 1968; F-25-4-2; 1 cm of textual records
    - Honours Admission Board Committee, 1968; F-25-4-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Library committee, 1968 - 1972; F-25-4-3; 1 cm of textual records
    - Library Committee, 1968 - 1972; F-25-4-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Search and selection committee, 1966 - 1972; F-25-4-4; 2 cm of textual records
    - Search and Selection Committee, 1966 - 1972; F-25-4-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
    - Search and Hire Committee, 1966 - 1972; F-25-4-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Steering committee, 1966 - 1968; F-25-4-5; 1 cm of textual records
    - Steering Committee, 1966 - 1968; F-25-4-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Student workload committee, 1971; F-25-4-6; 1 cm of textual records
    - Student Workload Committee, 1971; F-25-4-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Teaching evaluation committee, 1967 - 1968; F-25-4-7; 1 cm of textual records
    - Committee on Teaching Evaluation, 1967 - 1968; F-25-4-7-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Tenure committee, 1969; F-25-4-8; 1 cm of textual records
    - Tenure Committee, 1969; F-25-4-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Undergraduate studies committee, 1968 - 1977; F-25-4-9; 2 cm of textual records
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1968 - 1971; F-25-4-9-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1972; F-25-4-9-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1973 - 1977; F-25-4-9-0-3 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Ad hoc committee, 1971 - 1976; F-25-4-10; 2 cm of textual records
    - Ad Hoc Constitutional Review Committee, 1971 - 1975; F-25-4-10-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
    - Ad Hoc Constitutional Review Committee, 1975 - 1976; F-25-4-10-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
  - Departmental Committees, 1968; F-25-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-12)
- Departmental reviews, 1974; F-25-5; 1 cm of textual records
  Series consists of materials relating to external and faculty reviews of the Department. It includes correspondence, memoranda, and reports.
  - Departmental review, 1974; F-25-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
- Course outlines and exams, 1965 - 1980; F-25-6; 11 cm of textual records
  Series consists of files of undergraduate and graduate course outlines and examinations.
  - Course Offerings, 1966 - 1968; F-25-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1974; F-25-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1974; F-25-6-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1974; F-25-6-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1975; F-25-6-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1975; F-25-6-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1975; F-25-6-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1976; F-25-6-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1976; F-25-6-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1976; F-25-6-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1977; F-25-6-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1977; F-25-6-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1977; F-25-6-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1978; F-25-6-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1978; F-25-6-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1978; F-25-6-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1979; F-25-6-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1979; F-25-6-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1979; F-25-6-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings, 1980; F-25-6-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Organization, 1965 - 1967; F-25-6-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - New Course Proposals, 1969; F-25-6-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
- Publications, 1974 - 1997, predominant 1974 - 1997; F-25-7; 2 cm of textual records
  Series consists of publications of the Department, including course offerings booklets.
  - Publications (Ephemera), 1974 - 1984; F-25-7-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-13)
  - Course Offerings Booklets, 1974 - 1997, predominant 1974 - 1990; F-25-7-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 25-14)
- Associations, 1965 - 1979; F-25-8; 11 cm of textual records
  Series consists of materials relating to professional associations to which members of the Department belonged. It includes correspondence and memoranda.
  - Association of Canadian University Teachers of English, 1967; F-25-8-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 25-14)